(760) 576 7555 devin1younge@gmail.com

I am a solutions-driven web developer with 4+ years of experience working on large and small-scale projects for various organizations. I also have 8+ years of experience in public speaking and marketing, providing live commentary for competitive gaming (Esports) events, both on-site and remote. I take a versatile approach, focusing on user experience and effective communication, and tend to favor simplicity and "what works" over rigid process. My ideal work allows me to combine creativity, coding, and collaboration to create something greater than the sum of its parts.

Languages and Technologies

Languages: JavaScript, Python, CSS3, HTML5, SQL

• Technologies: React, Node.js, Bootstrap, Git, Django, Gatsby, Apache

• Other: Kanban, MS Office, Google Suite

Work Experience

Live Commentator in Esports

Riot Games/Freelance

2014 - 2022

Berlin, Germany

- Provided commentary for over 40 professional events, spanning 8 different game titles across 13 countries.
- Produced dozens of audio/video content pieces and conducted hundreds of live interviews, on and off-camera.
- Effectively coordinated across international teams for production, marketing and event planning.
- Founded and developed English broadcast of Chinese *League of Legends* professional league, attracting an audience of over 20,000 viewers within 6 months.
- Increased YOY live viewership for major recurring League of Legends broadcasts:
 - EU League Championship Series: Peak Views: 35.5% increase, Average Views: 12.5% increase (2016-17)
 - Oceanic Pro League: Peak Views: 41% increase, Average Views: 59% increase (2019)
 - o Pacific Championship Series: Peak Views: 71% increase, Average Views: 71% increase (2021)

Jr. Java Developer ResMed 2012 - 2014

Compliance Software team

San Diego, CA

- Built and maintained software powering communications on over 20.5 million medical devices.
- Implemented solutions to simplify compliance process for insurance providers and doctors.
- Improved agile development process through data-driven iteration, leading to faster release cycles.
- Developed encryption algorithms to protect customer communications and anonymize healthcare PII.

Student Software Developer

University of Colorado

2011-2012

Office of Information Technology

Boulder, CO

- Developed tools and plugins for JIRA and Confluence-based inventory system.
- Catalogued and maintained MySQL database of various university computer equipment.
- Implemented and maintained custom web testing solution with jQuery.

Software Developer Intern

SD Supercomputer Center

Summer 2010

PMaC Lab

San Diego, CA

- Developed Java desktop GUI for manipulating and analyzing large weather datasets.
- Created server-side test suite for existing programs in Perl.
- Deployed LAMP-based website for results analysis.

Education and Certifications

•	Certificate: HTML, CSS and JavaScript for Web Developers, Johns Hopkins University	2023
•	Certificate: International Engineering, German, University of Colorado, Boulder	2012
•	B.Sc. Computer Science. University of Colorado. Boulder	2008 - 2012

Projects

- **Wetter** React and Bootstrap-based weather application, using weatherAPI. Created to explore the basics of React, consuming and analyzing public APIs, and asynchronous JavaScript. See source on Github.
- Prio Vanilla JavaScript and Bootstrap-based task list application. See source on Github.
- QuestMap Interactive map tool for Tabletop RPG players, built with Django and making extensive use of the Leaflet.js map library. Intended to increase game immersion with customizable interactive maps, mimicking the UX of classic adventure video games. See source on Github.
- **WisdomBall** A simple "fortune-teller" style web application, providing users with a randomized snippet of wisdom. Built to explore simple HTML/CSS/Javascript concepts. See source on <u>Github</u>.
- **Aliems!** Python-based *Space Invader* clone created with PyGame. Built to explore basic concepts in game development and extending my knowledge of Python. See source on <u>Github</u>.

Interests

- I write and publish TTRPG supplements, particularly adventures for *Dungeons and Dragons* 5th edition. Most of my work is available on the <u>DM's Guild</u> marketplace.
- I collect and read works of classic fiction, especially Sci-Fi and Horror.
- I am conversational in German, and maintain an interest in German culture.